Ethan Georgi / Web Development Email: ethan.georgi@gmail.com

Code Examples: http://github/ethancodes

OVERVIEW

With a background in Computer Science and more than fifteen years developing for the web, I have experience with numerous technologies. Self-motivated and efficient, I am capable of taking on multiple projects and producing impressive results. A creative problem-solver and eager to learn, I would be a valuable asset to any development team. I am looking for a challenging and fulfilling position which allows me to put my abilities to good use and encourages professional growth.

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

- Proficient with HTML and CSS, and taking advantage of HTML5 and CSS3
- Extensive use of JavaScript, jQuery and jQuery UI
- Forms, slideshows, menus and navigation
- Numerous implementations of responsive design
- Media queries, JavaScript, AJAX and PHP
- Multiple devices, varying complexities and content
- Familiarity with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to turn designs into HTML/CSS
- Development with WordPress
 - Custom functionality and Post types
 - Page templates and themes
 - Security
- Drupal expertise
- Custom theme development for specific web applications
- Module development with Forms API, Views API, and hooks
- Drupal administration, technical support and training
- Extensive experience with versions 6, 7 and 8
- · Familiarity with social networking APIs
- Handy with XML but prefer JSON
- SEO friendly
- Enthusiastic about documentation and version control (Git, Subversion)
- A bajillion years of experience with LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP)

WORK HISTORY

Overit Media, March 2013 to December 2016, Web Developer

• Overit Media is a digital marketing firm. The small development team worked closely with design and strategy teams to build everything from small websites for brochures and event promotion to incredibly complicated suites of software to support thousands of users.

- Responsibilities included back-end implementation using WordPress or Drupal, and front-end development using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and responsive web design techniques. Additionally, regular maintenance and support was provided for projects, which included upgrading core and plugins, performance improvements and debugging end-user issues.
- Many recent projects required massive amounts of custom module development for Drupal 8.

Zone 5, May 2008 to February 2013, Web Developer

- Zone 5 is a marketing and communications agency. Their Web Services group is a small team helping to develop solutions for higher education, healthcare, and technology industries.
- Projects ranged from on-line viewbooks that integrate with social media, to massive applications that allow users to apply for technical certification. Many projects involved working with designers and front end implementation, using existing APIs and libraries, and developing custom functionality.

MountainMedia.com, Inc, February 2007 to April 2008, PHP Developer and System Administrator

- Mountain Media offers hosted e-Commerce solutions for small to medium businesses. Each website is developed individually, with a custom graphics implementation, utilizing a shared code base.
- Responsibilities included, but not limited to, design, development, maintenance, and support of new modules, custom scripts, and reports, documentation, design of application architecture, technical support for graphic designers and clients, server maintenance, mail and mailing list administration.

HostRocket.com, Inc, June 2006 to January 2007, PHP Developer

- HostRocket.com, Inc. is a webhosting company offering hosting services for a variety of private and corporate entities. It's sister company ViaTalk offers broadband phone service to residential customers.
- Responsibilities include upper level technical support for ViaTalk technicians and customers, development and maintenance of new ViaTalk features, implementation of new control panel interface for HostRocket clients.

Eden Communications, Inc, August 2004 to April 2006, Lotus Notes Developer

- Eden Communications, Inc. creates service management software for companies of all sizes. Packages included Help Desk, Asset Management, and Project Management and are useable in both the Notes Client and a web browser.
- Responsibilities included gathering requirements from clients for customizations, writing of technical specifications, development and testing of customizations, Domino administration, and technical support.
- IBM Certified Application Developer Lotus Notes and Domino 6/6.5 First Albany Corporation, May 2001 to August 2003, Application Developer
- First Albany is a financial institution dealing in stocks, bonds, mutual funds and money markets, with offices all over the United States.

• Responsibilities included development and maintenance of applications and data used for financial research, client services, and internal workflow, as well as technical support and Domino server administration.

Marist College, June 1999 to February 2001, Application Developer

- Marist College is a liberal arts school located in Poughkeepsie, NY, with strong involvement with IBM.
- Responsibilities included technical support for staff and faculty, deployment of Domino servers, creation and maintenance of Domino user accounts, maintenance of existing application on various platforms.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science from Marist College (1999) Studied software development lifecycle, algorithms, object oriented programming, compiler design, database design, etc. Used Java for many major projects.